A Guide to the Sara Teasdale Collection
University of Virginia Library
- LETTERS
  - Nancy K. [Coonsman], St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Oct 20; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    praising her book and her expression of her "love in terms of nature," and wishing to see Sara
  - Marguerite Wilkinson, Coronado, California, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Oct 21; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    thanking her for
    and commenting on her growth
  - Harriet Monroe, Poetry, Chicago, Illinois, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Oct 23; ANS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    mentioning the review of her new book to be in December's issue
  - Edgar Lee Masters, Chicago, Illinois, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Oct 23; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    praising her new book and expressing his pleasure in having met her and Ernst B. Filsinger in St. Louis
  - Edgar Lee Masters, Chicago, Illinois, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Oct 25; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    stating that he received her new book through Harriet Monroe and will place it among his memorable things, and revealing some feelings toward war
  - Stuart Walker, Morgan Hill, California, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Oct 25; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    mentioning his health, the pleasant publicity of his
    Portmanteau
    , and her book
  - Kendall Banning, Chicago, Illinois, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Oct 25; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    requesting a contribution for a select anthology of Pierrot and Columbine poems
  - G. Schirmer (Inc.), New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Oct 25; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    requesting permission to use her poem "The Kiss" in a musical setting
  - Nathan Haskell Dole, Boston, Massachusetts, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Oct 26; ALS, 8 p. on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    thanking her for the volume and telling anecdotes about himself
  - Amy Lowell, Brookline, Massachusetts, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Oct 27; ALS, 6 p. on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    expressing admiration for her and pleasure at her kind words concerning her own work
  - Julia Scott Vrooman, Washington, D. C., to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Oct 29; ALS, 5 p. on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    expressing her delight upon receiving and reading her "exquisite little volume"
  - Vachel Lindsay, Springfield, Illinois, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Oct 30; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    , encouraging her and Ernst B. Filsinger to go to the Poets dinner, and mentioning receipt of the Chicago first prize for "the Chinese nightingale" and the progress of his Movie-Book
  - Blanche S. Wagstaff, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Oct 30; ALS, 3 p. on 3 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    expressing her pleasure in reading
    and promising a review shortly
  - Louis Untermeyer, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Oct 30; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    praising her blank verse in
    , and mentioning works by himself and his wife, Jean, and the opinions of Robert Frost and Max Eastman
  - Bart B. Howard, The St. Louis Republic, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Oct 31; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    expressing his fondness for her
  - Frederick Jacobi, San Leandro, California, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, [1915 Oct]; ALS,; 3 p. on 1 l., w/enclosure, w/env. (Box Box 6)
    requesting permission to publish her poem "The Kiss" in a musical setting
  - [ ], Department of English, Washington University, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Nov 2; ALS, 3 p. on 3 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    praising her work and commenting on the Rieder translation
  - Edward J. Wheeler, Editor, Current Opinion, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Nov 3; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    praising the "wonderful lyric qualities" of
    , saying that the "songs are so directly from the heart and life not only of a true poet but of a true woman..."
  - Ada Foster Murray Alden, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Nov 5; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    expressing her and her husband's, Henry Mills Alden, admiration for her `singing leaves'
  - Helen Bullis Kizer, Spokane, Washington, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Nov 9; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    praising her
    and her ability to "bring a seeing eye to the most outworn or ordinary situations..."
  - Kendall Banning, The Players, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Nov 12; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    commenting that she is "writing the best singing verse in the country today" and that "our singers are all too few and our Ezra Pounds and Gertrude Steins are all too many!"
  - Blanche M. Blake, Tennessee Federation of Women's Clubs, Nashville, Tennessee, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Nov 13; ALS, 2 p. on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    admitting to being an admirer of her poetry, and planning to read "Off Capri" to The Centennial Club
  - Herma N. Clark, Chicago, Illinois, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Nov 17; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    telling her plans to write an article on Carl Vrooman and Julia Scott Vrooman and wishing to quote from Sara Teasdale's verses
  - Marguerite Wilkinson, Coronado, California, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Nov 18; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    commenting on her "very unusual lyric gift" and the satisfying
    , and mentioning Sara's fragile health
  - Edward Bliss Reed, Yale Review, New Haven, Connecticut, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Nov 20; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    citing her work as "sincere and artistic," thanking her for the German versions of her poems, and wishing to publish some of her verse in the
    Yale Review
  - Louis Untermeyer, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Nov 21; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/enclosure, w/env. (Box Box 6)
    discussing an enclosed review of her
    , remarking on the sign of prodigy in Stephen Vincent Benet(younger brother of William Rose Benet), mentioning his wife Jean Untermeyer's hit with Amy Lowell, and likens one of G. K. Chesterton's poems to Vachel Lindsay's style
  - Miles M. Dawson, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Nov 23; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    quoting praises from Mrs. Meynell about the verses of Sara and of Margaret Widdemer as well as expressing his and his wife Grace Dawson's delight with them, and mentioning his new book
    The Etchics of Confucius
  - Robert W. Wilkes, Yonkers, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Nov 26; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    requesting permission to set to music her poem "Spring in War Time"
  - Alice Carter Butler, Chicago, Illinois, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Nov 27; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    praising
    and especially "The Answer"
  - Anna Catherine Murphy Markham, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Nov 28; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l., w/enclosure (review of Edwin Markham's California the Wonderful), w/env. (Box Box 6)
    sharing her admiration of "the lilt and the lift of the poems" in
    , mentioning Jesse R[ittenhouse], Margaret Fuller, Margaret Widdemer, Royal Dixon, and discussing the hardship of the family of the late Madison Cawein
  - Editor, Harper's Magazine, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Dec 1; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    accepting her poems "In a Hospital" and "Flames" for publication
  - Marie DuBois McCormack, Recording Secretary, The Wednesday Club, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Dec 8; ALS, 2 p. on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    informing her that they have elected her an honorary member
  - William H. Hills, The Writer: A Monthly Magazine for Literary Workers, Boston, Massachusetts, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Dec 9; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    requesting a personal biographical sketch of her by one of her friends
  - Arthur Guiterman, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Dec 11; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    thanking her for her "melodious book" and commenting on some of his favorite poems
  - H. L. Mencken, Editor, The Smart Set, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Dec 13; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    asking about `The New Moon' and the series of hospital songs, and thanking her for an article by Harris Merton Lyon
  - Edgar Lee Masters, Chicago, Illinois, to Ernst B. Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Dec 15; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    discussing Willard Huntington Wright's critical pen, and praising Sara Tesdale's songs
  - H. L. Mencken, Baltimore, Maryland, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Dec 20; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    expressing pleasure at one of her stories and wishing she would do more prose
  - W. K. Kelsey, Detroit, Michigan, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Dec 22; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    concerning
  - Editors, The Smart Set, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Dec 22; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    offering fee for her story "The Black Hearth"
  - Williamina Parrish to Vine (Colby) McCasland, 1915 Dec 24; ALS, (Box Box 6)
    sending an affectionate holiday letter
  - S[olomon?] L[eopold?] Millard Rosenberg, Lansdowne, Pennsylvania, to Ernst B. Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Dec 28; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    praising Sara Teasdale's
    and saying that no other American poet "so feelingly, so spontaneously and beautifully senses the primal human emotions"
  - Amy Lowell, Brookline, Massachusetts, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Dec 28; TLS, 3 p. on 3 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    thanking her for the copy of [
    ] and commenting on her favorite poems and on one fault, and promising to send a copy of her own
    Six French Poets
  - Williamina Parrish to Vine (Colby) McCasland, [1915]; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 6)
    sending some old photographs of Vine
  - Katharine Howard, Salt Lake City, Utah, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Jan 3; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    explaining that she does her readings "all for love of the fine new movement in poetry," and requests a copy of
  - George M. Whicher, Hunter College, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Jan 14; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    welcoming her book in their Poets Corner, praising her work, and inviting her to the College to see the work they are trying to do for the young women...
  - Julia Pauline Leavens, New York Browning Society, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Jan 15; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    mentioning her stay at the Dawsons' ( Miles Dawson and Grace Dawson) where she saw Sara's bridal picture
  - Harriet Monroe, Editor, Poetry: A Magazine of Verse, Chicago, Illinois, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, 1916 Feb 1; TLS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    requesting formal permission to include some of her poems in an anthology of the
    New Poetry
    , with a personal handwritten note at the bottom and on the verso
  - Salomon de la Selva, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Feb 4; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    expressing his interest in translating some of her work into Spanish and asking for her published books and a photograph
  - Hermina Earnest, Dallas, Texas, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Feb 10; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    requesting permission to publish "The Kiss" set to music
  - Mary James, student at Central State Normal, Edmond, Oklahoma, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Feb 10; ALS, 4 p. on 4 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    discussing a school project and requesting a letter and a photograph
  - Edward Bliss Reed, Assistant Editor, The Yale Review, New Haven, Connecticut, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Feb 24; TLS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    accepting her "Songs in a Hospital" and requesting one other poem for publication
  - Vine Colby, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Feb 25; ANS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    praising Sara and her work on behalf of "Ned" ( Edna Wahlert) and herself, and enclosing an "honest tribute from Ned"
  - Editors, Smart Set, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Feb 25; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    acccepting her poem "Old Days" for publication
  - Sara Teasdale Filsinger, Usona Hotel, St. Louis, Missouri, to Vine Colby, [St. Louis, Missouri], 1916 Feb 28; ALS, 4 p. on 2 l. (Box Box 7)
    expressing her satisfaction at hearing from her and Ned ( Edna Wahlert)
  - Alfred Edward Housman, Trinity College, Cambridge, England, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Feb 28; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    thanking her belatedly for her gift of
  - John Masefield, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, 1916 Feb 28; ALS, 1 p. (Box Box 7)
    thanking her for the letter and gift of poetry
  - Clara Root Farr, Clinton, Oklahoma, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Feb 29; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    concerning her own article on "Masterpieces of American Women Poets"
  - Mary S. Wright, Editorial Department, The Davenport Democrat and Leader, Davenport, Iowa, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Feb 29; TLS, 2 p. on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
  - May Massee, Editor, A. L. A. Booklist, Chicago, Illinois, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Mar 4; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    , and mentioning it being listed in the April issue
  - Lucia Sloan Hopkins, College Club, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Mar 7; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    extending an invitation for her to read some of her poems at a benefit tea
  - Robert Bridges, Scribner's Magazine, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Mar 8; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    accepting her poem "Child, Child" for publication if it is not to be published in a book soon
  - Gilderoy Scott, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Mar 15; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    expressing his pleasure with her letter, poems, and songs as well as his enjoyment in singing her songs, and mentioning a singing engagement at the Browning Society Soiree
  - Louise McNair, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Mar 15; ANS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    writing of her enjoyment in hearing Ernst B. Filsinger read Sara's poems at The Wednesday Club, and inviting her to tea with Celia Harris and herself
  - Ezra Pound, Kensington, England, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Mar 17; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    thanking her for the book which has not yet arrived and sending regards to "Johns and Miss Monroe"
  - Jane Burr, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Mar 19; TNS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    re
  - Merle St. Croix Wright, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Misouri, 1916 Mar 28; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    calling her new book delightful and commenting on her ability to "keep command over so sure an artistry," and enclosing a copy of his poem "To St. Louis"
  - Witter Bynner, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Mar 28; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    expressing pride at her letter and gift of
  - A. Walter Kramer, New York, New York, to William Marion Reedy, Editor, Reedy's Mirror, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Mar 28; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    requesting permission to obtain the rights to Sara Teasdale's poem "Joy" to use in a musical setting, with ANS from Reedy to Sara Teasdale Filsinger at top
  - L. Camilieri, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Apr 4; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    thanking her for the letter and beautiful book, and expressing an inerest in setting some of her poems to music
  - Horace Johnson, Waltham, Massachusetts, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Apr 4; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    indicating that he has set to classical music her poem "Flames"
  - Grace L. Dawson, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Apr 8; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    writing of activities of the Browning Society and enclosing a program
  - Francis Grierson, Burlington, Iowa, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Apr 8; ALS, 2 p. on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    expressing his certainty that some of her lyrics will inspire some composer to set them to music
  - Susie Willis, Kansas City, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Apr 13; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    wishing to secure the "Song Maker" and one other lyric for use in a vocal number in "Missouri's Place in Literature"
  - R. Huntington Woodman, Brooklyn, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Apr 16; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    thanking her for the gift of
    , and expressing an interest in setting some of them to music
  - William Faversham, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Apr 19; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    thanking her for the pretty "Mary Arden poem"
  - Adelaide Forshaw, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Apr 30; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    enclosing three photographs of William Faversham and others at the Shakespeare Celebration
  - Cedric W. Lemont, Chicago, Illinois, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 May 1; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    requesting permission to use "The Kiss" in a musical setting
  - William Arms Fisher, Oliver Ditson Company, Boston, Massachusetts, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 May 2; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    thanking her for the letter and copies of her poems, and mentioning a discussion with Edmund Clarence Stedman over what constitutes a lyric poem
  - Frank Howard Warner, New York, New York, to The MacMillan Company, New York, New York, 1916 May 7; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 7)
    requesting permission to set to music Sara Teasdale's poem "I Heard a Cry"
  - Henry Wellington Wack, Newark, New Jersey, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 May 10; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    concerning Newark's Poem Competition and its civic theme
  - Lee Shippey, Missouri Writers Guild, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 May 19; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    requesting her membership and expressing admiration
  - Ray Werner, The St. Louis Art League, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 May 20; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    concerning her assistance as judge
  - William Butler Yeats, London, England, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 May 27; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    thanking her for her letter and poems, which gave him a great deal of pleasure
  - J. W. Cunliffe, Columbia University, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 June 9; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    requesting permission to use her poem "In a Hospital" in a volume of selections from English and American poets about the war to be edited by himself on behalf of the Belgian Scholarship Committee
  - Joyce Kilmer, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 June 17; TLS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    concerning a meeting of American poets to be held on June 28 "in memory of Padraic Pearse, Thomas MacDonagh, and Joseph Plunkett, the three poets who were executed for their share in the recent uprising in Dublin, " and asking for one of her poems to be read
  - Robert Bridges, Scribner's Magazine, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, Cromwell Hall, Cromwell, Connecticut, 1916 July 8; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    enclosing a request to set to music "Child, Child"
  - Louise Holdren Anderson, The Drama League of America, Chicago, Illinois, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, 1916 July 11; ALS, 2 p. on 2 l. (Box Box 7)
    extending appreciation for her part in the St. Louis Convention, and commenting on her two beautiful odes read by William Faversham
  - Ferris Greenslet, Houghton Mifflin Company, Boston, Massachusetts to [Sara Teadale Filsinger], 1916 July 13; TLS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    offering preliminary terms for the spring 1917 publication of her anthology of love lyrics by women
  - Ernst B. Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, Cromwell Hall, Cromwell, Connecticut, 1916 July 17; TL, 1 p. (Box Box 7)
    concerning Houghton Mifflin Company's acceptance of Sara's
    The Answering Voice...
  - Ernst B. Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, Cromwell Hall, Cromwell, Connecticut, 1916 July 17; TL, 1 p. (Box Box 7)
    more concerning
  - Grace Clarke Pierce, Indianapolis, Indiana, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 July 17; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    requesting copies of her two Shakespearian odes both read by William Faversham
  - Grace Hazard Conkling, Northampton, Massachusetts, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, Noharet, Massachusetts, 1916 Aug 6; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    thanking her for her charming note about her daughter Hilda Conkling's poem, and enclosing some poems by the five-year old
  - Fay Foster, Alton Bay, New Hampshire, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, Charlevoix, Michigan, 1916 Aug 11; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    requesting permission to set to music her poem "A Poem of Young Love"
  - Anna L. Moss, Douglas, Michigan, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1916 Aug 18; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    expressing her enjoyment over
    , and mentioning Sara's discriminating comment on Sappho
  - Jenkin Lloyd Jones, Director, Abraham Lincoln Center, Tower Hill, Wisconsin, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, Charlevoix, Michigan, 1916 Aug 19; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    requesting permission to print her "Testament" in a little volume of sermons
  - Henry A. Bellows, Vice-President, The Bellman, Minneapolis, Minnesota, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, Charlevoix, Michigan, 1916 Aug 21; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    accepting a poem for publication
  - Fay Foster, Alton Bay, New Hampshire, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, Charlevoix, Michigan, 1916 Aug 29; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 7)
    requesting again permission to set to music her "A Poem of Young Love" as well as "When I am Dead"